# Jose Gomez

# **FRONT-END** WEB DEVELOPER

Mobile: 832.613.3881

Email: gomez.jose853@gmail.com Web: josegomez832.github.io

#### LANGUAGES

- HTML/5
  - PHP
- · CSS/3 JavaScript
- MySQL Meteor
- ¡Query

#### **SKILLS**

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Sublime Text 2
- Sketch
- · SEO
- UI/UX
- Grunt
- Bootstrap
- · Responsive Design
- · SASS
- WordPress
- Git

#### **Awards**

- 2014 Honory Mention for The Shops at Houston Center
- · 2016 Latern Award for Raizner Law Landing Page

# **PROFILE**

I am a creative web developer and designer with over 5 years of agency experience. I provide rapid, robust and client-acclaimed front-end development optimizing user experience, search engine ranking, usability and accessibility. Able to complete projects efficiently and satisfy clients with attractive, user-friendly websites.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Forthea Interactive Marketing**

#### Web Developer

April 2016 - Present

- Develop WordPress sites for clients such as Andrews Myers, Fine Watch Bank. Almost Home Properties, The Buckley Law Group, and Chipman Relocations
- Work with SEO and PPC team to design and develop strategic landing pages to ensure conversion rates
- · Create website launch list and install SSL Certificates for all client sites going to production
- · Meet with clients to gather requirements for site design and help Project Manager create timelines.

# **MMI** Agency

#### Web Designer / Developer

May 2012 - April 2016

- Design and develop over 15+ responsive WordPress sites which include landing pages, blogs, ecommerce, business and multilingual websites
- Create strategic landing pages that are optimized for conversions
- · Responsible for developing Intranet portal for employees to post updates, add calendar invites and search other employees
- Design and develop innovative marketing email campaigns with 25% clickthrough rate
- · Create training manuals in PDF format on WordPress for clients such as Shell Houston Open, Air Liquide Health Care, American International Group and The Shops at Houston Center
- · Produce sketches, wireframes and clickable prototypes for testing and illustration purposes

# **Elemental Media Group**

## Intern Web Developer / Designer

October 2011 - December 2011

- Developed custom XHTML/CSS website
- · Implemented WordPress on existing static site
- Created social media graphics

### **EDUCATION**

#### The Art Institute of Houston

2009 - 2012

Bachelor of Fine Arts with a Major in Web Design & Interactive Media